so the first technique for reducing the
Mis rate is using larger cach blocks
they help the Mis rate because more
words are brought in when we have a miss
so subsequent axises that might access
those additional words we brought in
will not be
misses and they would be misses if we
had a smaller cach block so this does
reduce the Mis rate but only when
spatial locality is good but when
spatial locality is poor the my rate
will increase because now what happens
is we bring in the word we need and
along with it now we bring more words
that we didn't need so
effectively our cachee now looks like a
lower capacity cach because it has more
junk in it so we end up suffering more
of those capacity
misses so if we plot the Miss rate and
how it changes as the block size changes
for a small cach we might get something
like this where the M rate drops as we
increase the block size but then starts
increasing as we exhaust the amount of
spatial
locality that the cach can
support but then it starts to grow as we
start to suffer from the Mis rate
increase because the there is not enough
spal locality for a 4 kilobyte cache
this might happen for example with a
block size of 64 interestingly however
for larger caches we will start out with
a lower Mis rate to begin with and it
will continue to drop up to larger block
sizes eventually it's going to start to
increase but here we might be looking at
for example 256 byte block size this
effect has to do with how much junk are
we putting in the cache and how much
room there is in the cache so some
blocks will have more locality than
others and then in a small cache those
that don't have enough spatial locality
are creating some junk and those that do
have a lot of spatial
locality are being placed in the cash
but there is not enough room for them
because of all the junk when we have a
larger cache for example 256 kiloby then
what happens is those blocks that don't
have enough locality put some junk in
the cash but the cash is bigger so it
can also contain those blocks that do
have spatial locality so the cache
tolerates a slightly bigger block size
so overall we can reduce the Miss rate
especially in a larger cache if we
increase the block size